ETHAN STARLING

ethan.jr.starling@gmail.com 317-509-9002 Indianapolis, IN www.linkedin.com/in/ethan-starling/

Profile

Driven, motivated Software Developer with experience in C#, multi-tasking, and ASP.NET driven by 500+ hours logged of coding time and training. Exposure to HTML and CSS while applying technical and critical thinking skills gained from those experiences. A strong background in leadership and customer service provides me an advantage to manage people and deal with different customer situations in a fast-paced environment.

Education

- Eleven Fifty Academy, Software Development Immersive Learning Program, Indianapolis IN, May 2022
 - 12-week immersive learning program for Software Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours logged of coding time and training
- Purdue University, Bachelor of Science in Geology, West Lafayette IN, December 2015

Competencies & Functional Skills

Problem solving, competent data management, multi-task management, customer service, deadline regulation, Agile methodology, portfolio development, troubleshooting

Technical Skills

Languages/Libraries: C#, ASP.NET, SQL Cloud Technologies: Azure, GitHub

CI/CD: Agile, Git

Databases/ORM: Entity Framework, SQL server, Relational Databases

Web Technologies: CSS, HTML, MVC, APIs, Bootstrap, Responsive web design

Testing Tools: MSTest

Technical Projects

Spongebob ASP.NET API

- Utilized C# and swagger to build an api for Spongebob show in which you can find specific characters, places and items.
- US Parks ASP.NET MVC Web application
 - Utilized HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap 4, and C# to design an mvc web application that allows the user to look up specific state and national parks and see the various attractions and nature within them.
- Several Business Console applications
 - Utilized C# to build out several console applications pertaining to the logic of businesses requests

Professional Experience

Fresh Thyme Market, Carmel IN. (2016 - Present)

Food preparation, quality control, customer service, training/mentoring of new employees

Ford Dining Court, Purdue University, West Lafayette IN, (2012 - 2015)

- Collaborated with cooks to serve meals in streamlined procedure, trained new employees, worked while in school Camp Kikthawenund, Frankton IN (2008 2011)
- Served as a primary lifeguard/swimming instructor and educated Webelos scouts of outdoor camping and safety

Accomplishments

• EFA Integrity Core Value Award | Eagle Scout